<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shanks&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>https://shanks.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shanks&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 14:56:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shanks.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0x4 - MagpieCTF 2023 Writeup Standings</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 14:56:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x4/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few weeks but I received some great news on March 28th 2023. I was one of the three winners for the MagpieCTF 2023 writeups portion.
They announced the winners in their Discord server on the announcements channel.
This was a big win for me since it was my first time attempting the writeups officially. I hope to bring more writeups in the future and furhter improve my skills to transfer the knowledge that I&amp;rsquo;ve gained through my experiences with this challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagpieCTF 2023 - This outta be large enough right?</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/binary/this-outta-be-large-enough-right/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 14:26:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/binary/this-outta-be-large-enough-right/readme/</guid>
      <description>We’re given a C source code file to analyze and its executable to test with.
Solution I would like to preface this, that I have done this exact challenge from PicoCTF 2022, called buffer overflow 1 and at the time I followed along with John Hammond’s solution video. As a result, when I saw this challenge, I immediately recognized it and thus I used the solution developed by John Hammond, and simply modified it for this challenges specifics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagpieCTF 2023 - No Password Here</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/binary/no-password-here/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 13:01:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/binary/no-password-here/readme/</guid>
      <description>This challenge had us look at a C source code file and try to find a way to cause a buffer overflow. Here is the compiled program and its lib.
Solution Opening the C file, we see that the file does not have the typical gets function that is well known for its vulnerabilities. Instead the function we have to focus on it scanf. If you aren’t aware, scanf does not have bound checking capability so if the input string is longer than the buffer size, then it will overflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagpieCTF 2023 - What is Password</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/networks/what-is-password/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 12:45:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/networks/what-is-password/readme/</guid>
      <description>This challenge had us look at a pcap file and look through the web traffic. The file can be found here.
Solution First we open the file in Wireshark.
Since the amount of web traffic is very small we can just analyze it manually. Notice the HTTP GET request for /Password.PNG in frame 4. After nearly 10 ACKs and PSHs, we get our server response code 200, HTTP OK in frame 15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagpieCTF 2023 - Chocolate Chips With Zero G</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/web/chocolate-chips-with-zero-g/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 23:36:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/web/chocolate-chips-with-zero-g/</guid>
      <description>This challenge had us visit our targets website, and look for an insecure admin portal.
Solution Default websites often have a login/admin.html/php web page for admin users to login and modify certain elements. Using this information we can quickly test it, it never hurts to try right? As such we find that http://srv1.2023.magpiectf.ca:1234/admin.html exists.
Note, you could have alternatively seen within the robots.txt that it disallows the traversal/crawling of /admin.html or you could have seen the invisible link within the nav bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagpieCTF 2023 - So Meta</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/forensics/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 23:35:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/forensics/readme/</guid>
      <description>This challenge had us look at 2 Portable Network Graphic (PNG) files that were mangled and half-destroyed. See below:
Solution In our terminal of choice, using the following command:
strings challenge.png We can see in the output that the challengers offered a hint: Have you heard of stegsolve? My answer: nope.
A quick search for stegsolve leads me to this GitHub repo containing a stegsolve tool.
We install the stegsolver tool on my virtual machine and ran the imagine combiner tool under the analyse tab to retrieve the flag:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagpieCTF 2023</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 23:35:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/ctf-writeups/magpiectf-2023/readme/</guid>
      <description>Time for my second CTF! Over the weekend (Feb 24-26 2023) I participated in my second CTF competition, MagpieCTF. It is hosted by the University of Calgary Information Security Club, geared towards beginner to intermediate level players. Since my first CTF left me a little disapointed as my team didn’t cooperate as one, I chose to tackle this one alone. Oh boy did that make it much more difficult.
As the rules prohibited players from asking third parties for solutions or methods of attack, I was left only with the power of browsing the web in research so I can learn of different methods to solve the challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x3 - ISSessions 2023 Standings</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 21:03:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some cool news came about yesterday. ISSessions had their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gu28GgjoEfQ&#34;&gt;recap&lt;/a&gt; meeting where they released some statistics from the CTF including the top 100 players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x2 - Note about the Cyber Advent writeups</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 19:25:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to help me improve my skills with Hugo, I figured I would mention something regarding the writeups for the Advent of Cyber.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x1 - First post</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 17:56:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog post using Hugo. Just getting the hang of this, tinkering around with configs and posts. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope this goes well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
