<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Shanks&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>https://shanks.dev/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Shanks&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 15:07:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shanks.dev/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0x8 - Joplin Server using Docker</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 15:07:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x8/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently migrated from Anytype to Joplin for my note taking and wanted to self host the cloud server. Because I currently host my website through GitHub Pages but wanted to use a subdomain to get it
Thanks to the docker compose sample file as well as this and this video from DB Tech, I was able to setup my Joplin Server on Portainer
Here is the official Joplin server guide</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x9 - Jellyfin Server using Docker</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 15:07:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x9/</guid>
      <description>I decided I wanted to host my own media server and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use Plex so I chose Jellyfin. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I set mine up using docker and Portainer.
Docker You can use docker compose or simply deploy the app through Portainer&amp;rsquo;s UI without docker compose. Replace any $ variable with your setting. Here are the settings that I used for my docker setup:
image: linuxserver/jellyfin:latest ports: - 1900:1900 # tcp - 8086:8086 # tcp - 7359:7359 # udp volumes: - .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x6 - Graduation from University</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:27:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x6/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I had my convocation. I finally completed my biggest academic struggle &amp;amp; achievement yet, graduating university with a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Computer Science. Having taken courses in nearly every semester during my time at university with the exception of my first summer semester, I am very proud to have achieved such a feat.
Regardless of how I felt about the education itself, the friends and networks that I created was certainly the most valuable part of the journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x5 - First North Sec Experience</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 16:27:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x5/</guid>
      <description>This year was my first ever attendance to the North Sec cyber security event. It is Canada&amp;rsquo;s largest cyber security event, consisting of 3 parts: the conference, competition (CTF) and trainings, spanning nearly a week. Depending on which package you buy, you will be given various &amp;lsquo;swag&amp;rsquo; and other items for the various events. In my case, I bought the early bird conference and competition combo since I was still a student at the time (students got a 50% off promotion code) and wanted to do some networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x4 - MagpieCTF 2023 Writeup Standings</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 14:56:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x4/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few weeks but I received some great news on March 28th 2023. I was one of the three winners for the MagpieCTF 2023 writeups portion.
They announced the winners in their Discord server on the announcements channel.
This was a big win for me since it was my first time attempting the writeups officially. I hope to bring more writeups in the future and furhter improve my skills to transfer the knowledge that I&amp;rsquo;ve gained through my experiences with this challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x3 - ISSessions 2023 Standings</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 21:03:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some cool news came about yesterday. ISSessions had their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gu28GgjoEfQ&#34;&gt;recap&lt;/a&gt; meeting where they released some statistics from the CTF including the top 100 players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x2 - Note about the Cyber Advent writeups</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 19:25:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to help me improve my skills with Hugo, I figured I would mention something regarding the writeups for the Advent of Cyber.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0x1 - First post</title>
      <link>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 17:56:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanks.dev/posts/blog-posts/0x1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog post using Hugo. Just getting the hang of this, tinkering around with configs and posts. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope this goes well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
